

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER · SOFTWARE ARCHITECTURE RESEARCHER · SOFTWARE REPOSITORY MINER

941 Bloom Walk, Los Angeles, CA 90089-0781, U.S.

□ (+1) 213-884-8846 | ■ ducmle@usc.edu | ★ lemduc.info | □ lemduc | 🖬 lemduc |

### **Summary**\_

Blends research experience in Software Engineering and Data Mining with diverse and practical trainings in the software industries of Vietnam, S.Korea and U.S. to offer solid skills in software design and development. Experiences include (1) mining software repositories/big data, (2) developing cloudbased applications and web services, (3) architecture design, recovery, and analysis, (4) software product line engineering.

## **Education**

**University of Southern California (USC)** 

PhD in Computer Science, Software Architecture Research Group (SoftArch), GPA: 3.87/4.00

Pohang University of Science and Technology (POSTECH)

MSc in Information Technology Convergence Engineering, Software Engineering Lab (SELab), GPA: 95.9/100.0

Hanoi University of Science and Technology (HUST)

BSc in Information Technology (Magna Cum Laude), GPA: 8.07/10.00

Los Angeles, U.S.

Aug. 2013 - May. 2018 (Expected)

Pohang, S.Korea

Aug. 2010 - May. 2012

Hanoi, Vietnam

Aug. 2005 - May. 2010

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

Bloomberg L.P.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

**NEC Laboratories America, Inc.** 

RESEARCH INTERN - COMPUTER SECURITY GROUP

**Veritas Technologies LLC** 

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN - EV.CLOUD PROJECT, PLATFORM TEAM

**Samsung Research America** 

RESEARCH INTERN - ADVANCED PRINTING SOFTWARE LAB

**Dasan Handysoft** 

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

**HDC Media Vietnam** 

PHP DEVELOPER & ASTERISK PBX ADMINISTRATOR

New York, New York, U.S.

June. 2018 - PRESENT

Princeton, New Jersey, U.S.

May. 2017 - Aug. 2017

Culver, California, U.S.

May. 2016 - Aug. 2016

Irvine, California, U.S.

Jun. 2015 - Sep. 2015

Seoul, S.Korea

Sep. 2012 - Jun. 2013

Hanoi, Vietnam

Aug. 2009 - Jun. 2010

US

### Skills

**Programming** Java (Proficient), Python, Linux Shell, PHP, JavaScript, C/C++

**Frameworks** Spark, Spring, OSGi, EMF, GWT, Joomla, Liferay, Microsoft Azure

**Databases** MySQL, MongoDB

Others Agile Development, MTFX, SVN, Git, Asterisk PBX

# Relevant Coursework

Software Engineering Advanced Algorithms Machine Learning Database Systems Software Architecture Artificial Intelligence Natural Language Processing Information and Data Modeling

Decision Support Systems Software Testing Advanced Operating Systems Information Security

### Honors & Awards

'Thesis in Three' - Best Presentation Award, Doctoral Symposium, ICSE 2016 2016 Austin, TX, USA Florence, Italy Awardee, ACM SigSoft CAPS Travel Support for attending ICSE 2015 2015

2014 Awardee, USC Doctoral Student Summer Institute Award Los Angeles, CA, U.S.

2013 Awardee, Vietnam Education Foundation Fellowship

Best Poster Prize, 3rd International Symposium on IT Convergence Engineering 2011 Pohang, S.Korea 2010 Awardee, Research Scholarship from National Research Foundation of Korea Pohang, S. Korea

2010 Awardee, Certificate of Merit for Excellent Graduation Achievement Hanoi, Vietnam

Duc M. Le · Curriculum Vitae APRIL 8, 2018